Good morning. You're watching te program
with Ted R and John Kuryaku. And John
Kuryaku is still in a tarantulafree
zone.
>> Yeah. Oh, I tell you. And I've got a
I've got a Starbucks for the first time
in two weeks. And life is good.
>> Life is good. Uh when are you returning
to the uh to the land of the mosquitoes?
>> Literally as soon as you hit the stop
recording button.
I'm I mean I'm kind of kind of jealous
but kind of not jealous. So both. Yeah.
Um it's definitely one of those mixed
bags. Thanks everyone for joining us. Uh
I'm Ted Running the board today. So
Robbie West is off. Um he is his prayer
session went ran long. God does that
sometimes. Um please like, follow, and
share the show. Uh if you'd like to
contribute, we still have the we're
still trying to iron out the kinks with
YouTube. Um and we think we will uh it
in a matter of days probably by next
week. But if you feel the urge uh and we
really could use it a lot uh feel please
feel please donate um to our PayPal
account. Thank to those of you who've
already done so. We really appreciate
you. That PayPal address is our email.
You can also email us there. And we've
gotten some emails over there, John.
I'll forward some of them over to you
and we're going to reply to those. I'm I
like replying to uh to people. So
>> yeah, that's important to me.
deprogrampodcast@gmail.com
is the PayPal and the email. I will
admit that if you PayPal, I'll probably
reply sooner than if PayPal because I'm
a capitalist at heart. Not really, but
I'm a communist at heart, but you know,
we're live in a capitalist system, so
that that's how it is. Um, lots to talk
about today. Um, John is on the some
some guy named Joe Rogan's show. Is that
a thing? It was quite an experience
yesterday. You know, you have to you
have to sign a non- non-disclosure
agreement uh before you go on on the
show. So, so I couldn't bring anybody
with me.
>> I couldn't tell anybody the address of
the studio or the location of the
studio. I wasn't allowed to take any
pictures.
>> Um I wasn't allowed to bring my phone in
with me. You know, that kind of thing.
Well, those are basic security
protocols. And frankly, I don't blame
them at all.
>> I'll tell you what, he had he had five
of the biggest guys I've ever seen.
Like right out of a WWE, you know,
>> so like a 19 like 1980s New York City
nightclub doorman.
>> That's exactly what they were.
>> Like refrigerators.
>> Exactly. And security cameras. Like
every inch of this compound was covered
by cameras and then an entire wall of
video monitors.
>> Chainling fence with with concertina
wire at the top. It was incredible.
>> Wow.
>> And it turns out that
>> he used to broadcast from the same
studio where Alex Jones broadcasts from.
>> Oh wow. Wow. and Alex Jones had one of
his reporters murdered just a few blocks
from the studio in June and um Oh,
>> so Rogan said, "I'm out of here."
>> Uh that that that seems reasonable.
>> Yeah. But security was very very
important and nice guy, very down to
earth, very normal, friendly, average.
>> He was a little bit late. He said there
was traffic. He came in about 10 minutes
late. We went straight into the into the
studio and there were no like
pleasantries or anything. He just
straight into it
>> for three hours. Yeah.
>> So, um that's great. So, yeah,
three-hour interview. I mean, it's like
it's funny, right? Because, uh you that
that's just an example of how the you
know, podcasting has really changed
things. Uh you know, it's like on
television if you got a five minute
interview that was a wide ranging long
interview. Oh yeah. Yeah. Exactly. And
three the funny thing about the three
hours was for the first hour he didn't
say a single word.
>> He he just kind of sat there looking at
me and then he was just like [__]
I didn't realize it was that bad. You
know, stuff like that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, I mean it's true that
when people hear stories like yours in
detail, it's the details that really do,
you know, bring it across. I mean,
that's how you experienced it. And even,
you know, even a even a one-hour
retelling is like obviously highly
compressed, right?
>> Highly compressed.
>> But still, I mean, you know, you
experienced it over the course of years.
I mean, hell, you're still experiencing
it.
>> Yeah.
>> And so to get this right now, right?
>> I mean, it never really leaves you. I
mean, even if you get a pardon, um, you
know, it's
>> it's I think the word I think the word
smeared from the McCarthy era is such a
good word for it because it's really
true. You you know, you you've been
psych you get psychically and
psychologically and spiritually smeared.
And, you know, you you can't ever really
wash it all away.
>> No. No. There's you. It's not possible
to fully recover from something like
this because it changes not just you but
the people around you,
>> right?
>> And and you can't you can't go back in
time and try to fix things. My my life
will never be the same.
>> Well, that's a good segue. Um maybe we
should get right into the the news and
obviously Gaza is at the top of the news
and Gaza is a place that um you know is
never going to be the same really. And
uh and I I think honestly Israel is
never going to be the same. I mean the
Israelis lost their humanity in this
whole thing. Um and uh I don't know how
they get it back. They certainly don't
get their reputation back. Um I got to
just say this one thing, this thought I
had, you know, now you know there's
going to be an influx of aid. There's
also going to be an influx of Western
news reporters and there and for the
first time there's not going to be any
denying on the part of of Israeli
apologists uh exactly what the the full
scale of what Israel did there. If
Israel thinks this is going to this is
the beginning of the road back to their
reputation, they're mistaken. It's going
to be the opposite. It's going to get
it's going to get worse as people see
what they did.
>> Yep. I think that's exactly right. And
you know, this is a pet peeve of mine
and I know that you know the Israelis or
their agents are watching this because
they watch everything.
>> Hi guys.
>> But there are a couple things that
bother me very much uh about this issue.
Number one, why in the world does the
mainstream media say Israeli hostages
and Palestinian prisoners?
Why? The Palestinians are hostages, too.
You just scoot people up off the street
and disappear them in prisons. They've
been kidnapped. They're hostages.
Same as yours are. They're hostile.
Number one.
>> Number two,
you know, we hear like, "Oh my god, the
Israeli hostage was released and he's
all skin and bones and they starved."
Have you looked at the Palestinians?
>> Yeah. In most by most accounts, the
Israeli hostages actually got the lion's
share of whatever food was available to
their captors.
>> That's right. The Israeli hostages were
treated better than the Palestinian
hostages were.
>> Oh, yeah. No, I mean, Palestinians have
died in in in captivity. I mean, there's
no evidence that um there's no evidence
that any uh I'm sure it's happened, but
I mean, there's no solid evidence that
Israeli hostages have been murdered. um
they've been killed by, you know, by IDF
bombing and shooting and stuff like
that.
>> Yes.
>> But, you know, and by the way, hostage
taking is not is obviously inexcusable
of civilians in particular.
>> Um but yeah, no, I I think it's like the
the narrative has just been way over the
top. So, we're going to talk about Gaza.
We're going to talk about Leticia James,
who um has been uh is now in the
crosshairs of the Trumpies. Um, I like
this story out of Chicago where a judge
basically has issued a formal order
saying, "Hey, quit beating up and
targeting journalists and protesters at
ICE protests." Um, like that guy from
Fox. Although, God, that spin machine
crazy.
>> I thought that was Antifa.
the Antifa PD. Uh Cuomo and uh Cuomo is
uh has picked up pretty much all of the
Eric Adams vote in the New York mayoral
race. Um but it's not going to be enough
to overcome uh Mamani's lead. Mandani is
going to be the next mayor of the city
of New York. And the president of Peru
has been impeached. I thought this was a
big story because it's unanimous, right?
I mean, the of course uh no, you know,
there's some crying today for the over
in the White House over the Nobel Peace
Prize, which did not go to Donald Trump.
It went to a right-wing Venezuelan
opposition politician. So, we'll get
into all that. What should we do first,
John?
>> Wow, there's so much. Um, you know,
let's let's do it let's do it a little
differently today. Let's let's hit some
of these smaller issues so we can we can
knock them out.
>> Let's do it.
>> Um, Maria Machado. Uh, now I'm going to
have to learn her full name. What's her
name?
>> Maria. Karina Machado.
>> Karina Machado. Machado. You know,
correct me, Ted, because I I'm not an
expert on Venezuela.
>> Nor am I.
>> I thought she was a
I thought she was like the female Juan
Guyaido.
>> She is. Yeah, that's basically it. Yeah.
Well, today the Washington Post is
saying that she now joins the ranks of
Nelson Mandela, Angansuchi and other
laurates who have challenged autocratic
rule. Well, Angansuchi is no hero. She's
a human rights criminal. But anyway, um
yeah, it was my understanding that she
was just another Juan Guyaido. She's in
hiding apparently, so it's unclear
whether she will be in Oslo
uh in person to accept the the peace
prize. Uh but I wanted to ask you, you
know more about about Venezuela than I
do. Do you think that this is part of
the Western effort to to weaken the
Maduro government?
>> Yeah, I do. Um it's it's really kind of
transparent and cheap. Um but I think
that's what it is. It's just literally
um you know like Maduro look Maduro's
under siege right I mean he's got US
warships right off the coast. He's got
US drones blowing up uh Venez you know
Venezuelan flagged boats that may or may
not be affiliated with drug cartels that
um uh you know he's already offed like
you know what 25 Venezuelan citizens or
more. Um you know God knows um you know
the pressure is on. That's not even
counting all the sanctions. And there's
a massive propag I think this is part of
the massive propaganda campaign against
the Maduro government. So, uh, you know,
it's kind of like Hugo Chavez 2.0. They
just, um, the US is determined to have a
puppet government in Venezuela as the
largest, uh, oil producer in the Western
Hemisphere. And I think it comes down to
that. I think it's really just that
simple. Um, it was a disappointing and
strange choice. I could have thought of
a lot a lot better choices. I mean, I
would have rather see Greta Thunberg get
it. You know what I mean?
>> You know, as much as that girl bothers
me, um, she deserved it.
>> You know, she actually like walks the
walk and deserves it.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, yeah, I have to agree with you.
>> So, yeah, we'll we'll follow that. Um,
and so let's we'll show Oh, then while
we're in Latin America, let's scoot over
to Peru. Um, I don't So,
>> yeah, I I didn't follow this at all. I
was surprised when I saw your note.
>> Yeah. Well, I I hadn't been following it
either. I mean, Peruvian politics are
always kind of weird to me. Um, but
basically, apparently the country has
been ravaged by a massive out of control
crime wave. Um, basically you can't
drive a bus in uh in in in Peru
apparently without being threatened with
death unless you are you pay out uh
shakedown money. Uh businesses have been
bombed in for you know for not paying
protection money. Basically extortion is
the national industry now in Peru. and
uh the gut the president who's just been
ousted, Dina Bulawarte, uh she's a uh
right sort of a center right I think
it's fair to say more right than center
um ruler and she had had pretty pretty
broad support but basically you know one
of the reasons you elect right-wingers
is for law and order and if you don't
get law and order there's no reason to
have her around so the in the provian
system uh one house of parliament right
I don't think they have a biccameal
legislature there. Um, one they they
they can remove the president and they
did and they did it unanimously
122 to zero.
>> Oh my god.
>> So it's a stunning rebuke. So she goes
from being president just like just like
that the stroke of midnight she's
unemployed. Um so she's basic so so
basically um there's all sorts of
thoughts that she may be fleeing into
exile to to go to Ecuador. The
Ecuadorians uh are haven't said whether
they're going to accept her or not, but
that would indicate to me that she's not
even viewed as like physically safe in
her own country. Um, there was a machine
gun attack
against in the middle of a concert on
Wednesday that killed uh the four four
members of the band while they were
playing.
>> Oh my.
>> So, people just basically are like
>> basically Congress is like, "Fuck this.
She's out.
>> I assume they'll have new elections."
See, and this is another country that's
having catastrophic
political developments and is utterly
ignored by the Western press and it's a
western country. I didn't know any of
this stuff.
>> No, it's true. Well, it's because the
the news is not good in our to say the
least. Question for you, John, from
Longhorn Clement. Did the topic of Mike
Baker come up on Joe Rogan's show? I
really wanted you to tell Joe how Mike
got fired from the CIA.
>> Well,
yes and no. The very first thing he
asked me when he walked into the studio
was, "Hey, do you know my friend Mike
Baker?"
And I said,
"Oh, sure. I've known Mike for years. In
fact, I replaced Mike in Athens and I
worked with his wife in London." And
then he says, "Okay, we're on the air."
Um, and then he just changed the the
subject. So that was literally all I got
to say was, "Yeah, I know."
>> That was it. And then he never came back
to Mike Baker again.
>> That's kind of analogous to the world of
cartooning where, you know, if you meet
another cartoonist and you say and they
say, "Oh, I know your work."
>> That means they means they don't like
you or your work. But it's like but they
know it.
>> I always say I admire your work.
>> See that's different. Yeah. Or I like
your work or your work is great or
whatever. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. So
we could we could we could talk about
Cuomo.
>> Yeah. Let's talk about Cuomo. So you
were right. You predicted that he was
going to get all or almost all of Eric
Adams support. And that's exactly what
happened. But with that said,
it's nowhere near enough to win this
race. And look, man, we're already on
the 10th of October.
Uh the the race the the elections in
three weeks and and I'm assuming that
>> it's actually earlier than that because
we have early voting here in New York.
>> That was my next sentence. Yeah. I've
already voted in Virginia for the for
the gubanatorial uh race. So, I just
assume New York City's is an advanced,
you know, an advanced
uh constituency that has early voting.
>> Well, New York City in many ways is not
an advanced country uh city. Uh you
know, I mean, we have a subway system
that still runs on DC power. Um but, uh
it's definitely Yeah, the we're we have
early voting uh and we have ranked
choice voting, but it's it's none of
that's going to matter. I mean,
Mandani's lead I I is obviously
insurmountable.
>> Yes.
>> Current poll shows um Mandani for at 46,
Cuomo at 33, Curtis Leewa, the
Republican nominee at 15.
>> Um so with a with an error message with
an error of plus or minus 4%. Which is
>> Did you see day before yesterday Rudy
Giuliani endorsed Curtis Leewa?
>> Oh well, I mean he is the Republican
nominee. Yeah, but but Giuliani was a
lifelong Democrat, was he not?
>> Well, he was, but not as mayor. I mean,
you know, he he ran as a Republican as
mayor,
>> but I mean, you know, the Republican
party line, you know, under under
Giuliani and Bloomberg was kind of just
sort of like lying around doing nothing.
So, it was an opportunity for
politicians who didn't who were
frustrated by the intricacies of the
Democratic machine in New York. like,
"Okay, I'll just step outside of that."
And everyone kind of like knew wink
wink, nudge nudge. I'm I'm for a woman's
right to choose. I'm I'm progay. It's
all fine. You know, I know I'm a
Republican, but
>> Right. So,
>> I'm one of the good Republicans. I could
just hear him saying it.
>> So, Cuomo, I mean, obviously, uh, you
know, the powers that be in New York
have to be accepting the reality here at
a certain point. Now, I'm interested in
seeing what's going to happen with the
landlords. Landlords are warehousing
about one out of four rental units in
New York City. Uh hoping for a law that
passed in 2019 under former mayor uh
mayor uh Delasio to change. They're
basically hoping that they're going to
be able to uh raise the rents uh under
going back to the pre209 rules. That's
look whatever Mandani happens does or
doesn't do, he's not going to reverse
that law. So the So when he So landlords
are going to have to come to Jesus and
they're going to have to decide do we a
try to figure out a way to like get rid
of Mandani like impeach him or
something. B, do we uh sit tight for
four years and keep these units
warehoused all this time and and collect
zero rent? Or do we do we internalize
the new valuations of our properties
that are worth now considerably less
than they were before 2019? And then
that would that last part would mean
that some landlords maybe many landlords
would walk away from their properties
and allow them to be abandoned or go
bankrupt or burn them down for the
insurance money as happened in the Bronx
in the 1970s. But it's going to be I
mean there's going to be repercussions
here, you know, in terms of the in terms
of the rent.
Tell me something, Ted. To to do
something like like to um
to, you know, revoke previous
legislation or whatever. Is that done by
the city council? And isn't New York
City's city council just gigantic?
>> Yes. Yes. John, you may not know, you
personally are on the New York City
Council. You just never showed up. Um
Yeah, we all are. Um you know, my cat is
Clovis. No, I mean know it is it is a
gigantic city council. I think I don't
even know. I think it's 65 members, I
want to say, if I had to put money on
it. It's absurd. And yes, um everything
has to go through city council. Um it's
a very left-wing um you know, basically
it's a DSA left-wing city council. I
don't think there's a single like
conservative on it. Um you know, a
conservative on the New York City
Council is basically like a Hubert
Humphrey Democrat. Um, and so they're
going to be um, so they're going to be
extremely acquiescent. They're going to
be very happy with this mayor. This
mayor is going to get along great with
city council. So, you know, they
anything they propose, he's going to
sign. Anything he proposes, they're
going to pass. So, that there's not
going to be gridlock in in city hall in
that way except for just the fact that
New York City just can't can't respond
to anything. I mean, for example,
there's a crisis with ebikes. Um, and
people are getting killed all the time
by speeding ebikes, but but the city
just can't, you know, doesn't seem to I
mean, just yesterday, I was listening to
local uh WNYC talking about like why the
city isn't doing anything. Well, there's
15,000 ebikes, John, so how are they
going to regulate them? I'm like, they
regulate 8 million New Yorkers. I mean,
how many cars are there in New York? How
many truck? There's 15,000. What does
that even mean? That's the stupidest
explanation in the world. But that's
what they that's literally what they
say.
>> Oh my god. Yeah. So, we're not we
shouldn't expect So, we're we're going
to expect Mandani to win, but we
shouldn't expect these cataclysmic
changes that so many people are
disingenuously uh predicting.
>> Yeah. Unfortunately, there's not going
to be hammer and sickle bunting over
Time Square,
>> as much as I would love to see that. Um,
so yeah. No, I mean, look, I I think the
thing is that
>> the mayor is he's this m this mayor is
going to have honestly one major problem
and nobody's talking about this. There
are three loai of of power in New York
City. The cops, the uh there's the uh
real estate, and there's Wall Street.
None of those are in Mumani's pocket.
Mumani has the voters, but that the
voters elect you, but you can't govern
without having one of them, right? Like
Giuliani had the police,
>> Bloomberg obviously had Wall Street, Ed
Cotch had real estate.
>> Um, you know, Delasio had nothing and he
was extremely ineffectual um as a
result. So Mumdani's problem is that
he's going to always have to go straight
to the New Yorker to to New Yorkers for
approval of anything. New Yorkers are
divided about a lot of issues that you
know out non- New Yorkers don't care
about like yeah you know um
>> a lot of stuff relating to schools like
do you do tracking or do you have you
know we have we have public we have high
schools that are for that are elite um
and they keep changing the rules as to
you know whether they're going to try to
make them more racially diverse or not
and you know schools like Bronx Science
and Styver which are you know very hard
to get into you per great math and
science scores Um, so the point is
they're going to argue about stuff like
that, but I think Madamani is not going
to. First of all, if he can freeze the
rent, that'll be like a year or two.
Okay? I mean, it's it's just and even
freezing the rent when the average
rental is $5,000 a month. Um, freezing
the rent isn't really that big a deal.
The rent's so high already. I mean, a
rent reduction would be significant. Um,
would matter more. And you know, as for
the the grocery stores that you know,
your friend, the Greek uh Gustades mag
magnet loves
>> like John Katimis,
>> it's going to have no effect because
there's going to be five stores for the
entire city of New York for 8 million
people. Who I don't care how big they
are, it's not going to make any
difference.
>> He's gonna he's going to move to St.
Petersburg, Florida. It's like promise.
>> Okay.
>> Don't let the door hit you on the ass on
the way out. Yeah.
>> So, yeah. So there's going to be like no
really truly um it's not the rise of
socialism. Um really truly you know what
is a democratic socialist? It's a it's a
liberal in the 60s. That's what it is.
>> Yeah. That's it. That's all. It's
literally that's literally all it is. If
you look at democratic socialism today,
we're talking about Lynden Johnson.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Totally.
>> With the Vietnam War aside, we're
talking about Lyndon Johnson.
>> Question here from Cle is there any
validity to recovering revenue from
empty living spaces by taxing landlords
uh for sitting on them?
>> It's a good question.
>> Yes. I mean, yes, you you look, the
thing is there's eminent domain. This
these properties could be seized. Many
of them commercial um you know, spaces
that have been boarded up and covered
with graffiti for years are obviously an
eyes sore. um you know you empty units
become prey for squatters and uh drug
dealers and stuff. So there's I I've
always said this. I think it should be
forget taxation. I think it should be
against the law to have a a unit remain
empty more than a certain period of
time. You could make that period very
long. You could say you know property
rights are very important. You could say
five years or whatever.
>> That is long. Yeah.
>> But at a certain I would say two years
would be like fair. like you got to rent
and it's going to yeah it would have a
depressing uh a depressing effect on
rent which we need a you know
desperately but yeah no and and you know
certainly a moderate solution would be
to t right now the landlords they can
take the they they can take deductions
on the very sizable ones on the uh
warehouse units so I hate that I mean
just get rid of the tax incentives that
they currently have and you know you'd
see more units come line.
>> Wow.
Yeah, I like your idea. Five years, you
know, in the greater scheme of real
estate is not really that terribly long.
>> No.
>> And it might put some pressure on um on
rental prices.
>> It would roll by. I mean, at a certain
point, they'd be like, "Ah, shit."
>> Yeah. I mean, I personally think, you
know, I mean, as a former son-in-law of
a landlord, um, you know, I never my he
always had the my father-in-law always
had the idea like it's better to have
low rent and and have someone occupying
that space all the time than it is to,
you know, give it than to have uh people
have a lot of churn. You always have to
clean, you have to paint, you you know,
and and every month is killer on that
spreadsheet when you see you have that
zero rent. You don't want that, you
know,
>> right?
>> You want you want tenants. I mean,
that's the point. That's what you're in
the business of.
>> Um, should we talk about Leticia James?
>> Yeah, let's do that. Seems kind of
mean-spirited. No,
>> it definitely seemed although what she
did to to Donald Trump was also
>> he was very mean.
>> A little meanspirited. Right.
>> So, it is kind of funny, right? Because
it's like a very So, Leticia James is
charged with um she took out she had
mortgages on two homes. She has a uh I
forget which is which, but she has a
house in New York. She has a house in
Virginia. I think the Virginia house is
a vacation home. Anyway, she when she
applied for her mortgage on the Virginia
house, um she claimed that it was her
she the form that she filled out for the
loan said that it was her primary
residence. When you take out a loan and
you on a house that's your primary
residence, you get a better interest
rate than when you when it's your second
when it's a vacation home.
Who knows what was in her mind when she
did that. Was she thinking who's going
to know who's going to care? Maybe maybe
she was just like if when you close on a
house and you have a pile of paper this
high and they just keep they just keep
to sign here, sign here, sign here, sign
here. And it's like, yeah, you you
promise you read all this. Uhhuh. I read
all this. So maybe she didn't do that.
She is the attorney general of New York.
So probably I think people like that
should be more careful. Um but anyway,
she's accused of uh having benefited in
$19,000
in in interest savings.
And so this John this is really trivial,
right? I mean it is it's a speeding
ticket. I mean she's being prosecuted
but no one's sending her to prison over
this. I mean
>> no she's not going to go to prison. No,
>> this is to annoy her. It's lawfare.
>> It is. It's lawfare. And I if you asked
Donald Trump, "Do you believe this is
lawfare?" He would probably say, "Sure,
of course it is." Just like her
prosecution of me was lawfare, he would
say,
>> right? And it was.
>> And it was. Yes. Yes.
>> I mean, look, Donald Trump lied to get
loan. Uh he basically said, you know,
hey, it's not the size of my apartment,
it's how I use it to get a loan. So he
kept he exaggerated about the um his
assets in order to have more collateral
than he really did have and got loan and
got loans he shouldn't have gotten as a
result. But so it's he basically
committed fraud to get the loan, but he
paid it back. I mean the the lender was
completely whole, which is really like
the main point of like these kind of
fraud laws. So it's a victimless crime,
but it's a crime. Um and you know he was
and he was hit hard, right? Like
hundreds of millions of dollars um for
this for these business records at the
time.
>> And so you know and so that's that had
to really hurt. I mean the Trump
organization I think is still not
licensed to do business in New York
State.
>> They're specifically banned from doing
business in New York State
>> and obviously that's where it started,
right? So that's a I mean that's that's
got to hurt. I mean obviously I'm sure
but look li Democrats are going to say
and they are saying that like uh you
know Donald Trump has obviously
weaponized the DOJ against his his
enemies including Leticia um he's
probably going to go he'll figure out if
he can figure out a way to go after
what's her name down there in uh Atlanta
the prosecutor the RICO prosecutor he
will right um you know he's he's gone
after James Comey there will be more.
Um, how do I mean, how do we feel about
this? I mean, I'm really torn. It's like
part of me thinks these are legit
prosecutions. These are people who did
bad things.
>> So, it's like this is again, it's kind
of like analogous to what we were
talking about yesterday. Americans like
the they like going after illegal
immigrants. They don't like the way
these deportations are are happening.
And similarly here, I think I like to
see public officials who are doing bad
things punished, but I don't like the
way this is being done. Does that make
sense?
>> It does. You know, I think really most
most of us and I would even include
myself in this um have these sort of
vague
ideological positions
and then we have trouble
laying them out for others and were we
in positions of authority where we would
have to implement them into policy, we
would be unable to do so. I don't think
this is unique to Donald Trump or to the
Trump administration. Like for example,
nobody wants to have undocumented
migrants here who are raping and
murdering people or carjacking people or
killing. Nobody wants
>> they can go.
>> Yeah, they can go. But what do you do? I
mean, it's not like they are carrying
little signs saying I'm a violent
illegal immigrant,
>> right?
And then the Trump response is just to
scoop up everybody, throw everybody out.
I I had to laugh. I I think I mentioned
this yesterday. I had to laugh when the
head of uh Latinos for Trump was scooped
up last week. He's he's in detention now
and he's being expelled imminently.
>> They had a picture of him with this big
sign, Latinos for Trump.
>> You can't make that up. It's awesome.
>> Joy Havana, buddy.
John, we never talked about it, but what
about the superintendent of the De Mo
public school system?
>> We We really have to talk about that
because there's actually more to the
story that I learned yesterday.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> What you're talking about is a scandal
that should never ever ever have
happened. There's a guy
who until last week was the
superintendent of schools for the city
of De Moine, which is the largest school
district in the state of Iowa. And
frankly, it's one of the largest school
districts in the Midwestern United
States
>> for sure.
>> So, um,
>> it's a real De Moines's a real city.
>> It's a city. A real city.
>> By the way, John, do you know what what
do you know how De Moines got named? I
love this story.
>> No idea. I just assumed it was a native
name. So, I don't know if it was
Louiswis and Clark, but it was like
basically western explorers were
traveling along that the river there and
um they had an a local Indian guide
helping them who um you know spoke
native languages. Um I think it was the
uh the Mohawk um uh language. I could be
wrong about that. But anyway, the point
is at one point the the the Americans
colonist said, "So, what's up ahead down
the river?" And the guy said, "Oh, uh,
he talked to a local. It's like, oh, De
Moine." And so they assumed this is
either like a place name or like a and
and they they were like, "Okay, we c we
Christian this De Moines." It came out
about five years ago. Linguists uh have
determined it's it means those
[__]
>> Oh my god.
>> Anyway, go ahead. So this this so about
five years ago
um the De Moines school district engaged
a search firm. They needed to to find a
new uh uh superintendent and so they
paid hundreds of thousands of dollars
for this search firm to uh identify a
group of candidates. So they identified
five, it was whittleled down to three.
They interviewed the three finalists.
They chose this guy uh as the uh as the
superintendent. Well, it turned out that
he didn't have a PhD in education. That
was made up. And um it turned out he
wasn't even an American citizen.
>> He was here illegally.
And apparently a year ago,
ICE was on him and they realized this
guy's a fraud. And so they went and
interviewed him. So he knew that this
was coming.
>> What?
>> He knew he was going to be scooped up,
but he never said anything to anybody.
And so last week, sure enough,
>> why did he go to ground?
>> Well, let's see this. He he tried too
late. So when they went to get him last
week, he jumped in his car and took off,
right? Then jumped out of the car with a
gun and ran. finally threw the gun away
and Ice got him.
>> What the [__]
>> That's what I said. Like, what?
>> That's awesome.
>> What was this guy thinking? So, now the
latest development is day before
yesterday. the De Mo school district
sued the search company
and the search company issued a
statement that well you know in the
interview process they should have
weeded him out if he wasn't you know
answering the questions properly and
they were like no we paid you to weed
him out
you didn't even bother to check his
academic credentials let alone whether
or not he was even an American
>> yeah I was going to say doesn't he have
to fill out an I9 form to be become an
employee.
>> Yes. And it was all fake
>> and it didn't come and Yeah. When you
when you do that, you can submit that to
what used to be the INS and you know and
and like they they they come back.
There's E-Verify, right? That's what
it's called.
>> Yes. That's right.
>> So they didn't everify clearly.
>> No, they probably said they did. Anyway,
I I've been so interested in this
because it's so nuts and the the system
fell apart at every step of the way and
it resulted I mean nobody got hurt or
anything but there's a lot of uh there's
got to be a lot of embarrassment and
this is going to cost this search firm a
lot of money.
>> Was he Well, I I should hope so. Um, you
know, I guess it all goes to show when
you outsource your uh your your your
[__] out to some company rather than
doing your own HR hiring, what kind of
thing can happen? Is there any word,
John, on like whether he was a uh good
superintendent? Was he good at his job?
>> By all accounts, he was terrific and
everything everything was moving
smoothly.
>> Oh my god,
it's crazy. Uh, John, we have an ad
which uh I'm going to read here. Uh, hey
football fanatics, are you ready for
some prime time NFL action? Tune in to
Westwood One for all the grid iron glory
you crave. From jaw-dropping touchdowns
to gamechanging plays, don't miss a
moment of the excitement. Catch every
snap, every tackle, and every victory on
Westwood One. You can listen to the NFL
on the NFL app, on the Westwood Sports
app, on Westwoodsports.com via Westwood
One station streams and by asking asking
Alexa to open Westwood One Sports. If
it's the NFL, it's on Westwood One. Um,
so John, um, so just a little bit of uh,
uh, housekeeping. Monday, no show
because uh, of of Columbus Day or
Indigenous Genocide Day, depending on
your preference, or both. Um, so we will
be back on Tuesday at at 9:00 a.m. Uh,
also please like, follow, and share.
Please consider donating. Uh, we we
definitely have had some financial
setbacks here due to YouTube and even
with Rumble, we're we're having some
glitches, which we're trying to figure
out, but um, we really love doing the
show and want to keep we want to keep
doing it. Obviously, we're all having a
good time here, so let's keep the the
party going. Um,
>> but so all right. Well, you know, this
is definitely going to be this would
have been a Lifetime Cable for women,
you know, afternoon movie.
>> Exactly.
>> The wacky superintendent
>> boyfriend. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. He Oh, yeah. Totally. Like,
I wonder if he lied to his family, too.
Right. Like,
>> oh my god.
>> It's uh Yeah. No, it's I mean, honestly,
I feel terrible for him. It must have
just been the stress of knowing that
you've built this house of cards that
can come crumbling time down any time
>> at any moment. At any moment.
>> Horrible.
>> Yeah.
>> And you know, it also kind of like makes
us think about, you know, imig
immigration policy, right? It's like
sort of like look, the guy did a good
job as superintendent. He was fine. You
know, he was an upstanding citizen
except for whole the whole like running
away and carrying a gun with the
possible obviously crossed his mind to
using it against law enforcement. Not
good. Um, you know, but overall maybe,
you know, it should make some people
think maybe we shouldn't have this level
of enforcement. Anyway, I don't know.
>> Ann Wilcox. Hi, Ann. Ann is saying the
De Mo superintendent was a beloved high
school principal in DC.
>> What?
>> I did not realize that.
Oh,
>> so he didn't just come out of the
woodwork. He he had experience, which
also means that the DC school board
never bothered to check the guy's
bonafites.
>> Well, I think it probably starts there,
right? Because I think once you've been
a principal in DC,
>> nobody's thinking like, let's see if
he's an illegal immigrant.
>> Yeah, that's right. That's right. Oh my
god,
>> that's
>> Oh my god.
>> Well, I kind of like admire the guy. Um
but uh while we're talking about
immigration stuff, John, um a judge has
uh so there's been all these protests.
It's really kind of interesting. So in
the run-up to the rise to Hitler's
seizure of power in 1933,
um the Nazis would go out into the
streets of Berlin and other German
cities and basically cause chaos. Like
they'd start street riots. They'd beat
up socialists and uh and and Jewish
people and other people, shopkeepers
that they didn't like. and they caused a
general atmosphere of unease and and and
criminality. And then Hitler ran for
chancellor partly on the on the grounds
of if you elect me, I can bring law and
order to Germany. And of course he could
because he was the cause of the disorder
and and I'm reminded of that u because
of you know basically we're being told
that that Portland and Chicago and these
other cities are quote unquote
hellscapes. If you watch, if you look at
my Twitter feed, it's all full of
right-wingers saying like, "Thank God,
we're going to save Chicago. We're gonna
save Portland." Uh, you know, President
Trump is going to save them from the
war, from the evil that's going on
there. But it's all self-fulfilling,
right? Because then meanwhile, lefties
who actually haven't been doing [__]
because lefties never do [__] um in
these cities, they're like now they're
pissed and they go to like the ICE
office in Portland and protest. So, it's
a self-fulfilling prophecy. It's kind of
the opposite of the 1933 thing. It's
like, oh, the, you know, we're going to
talk up the disorder, which will
actually cause the disorder, which we
will then claim we're ending, right?
Basically, um, it's kind of clever. It's
weird that it works in in an era of
super hyper communications. But anyway,
the judge is banning uh Homeland
Security agents from going after
journalists or protesters with riot
weapons at ICE sites. They say first you
have to warn someone that you're
interested in in stopping twice with
your voice and you have to have visible
IDs. Um and uh if you if those two
warnings uh like for example to disperse
or whatever are ignored then you can
step in and use but basically the judge
has sided with the journalists who say
that the journalists are being sided.
DHS says like well you know we tried to
protect journalists but you know it's a
dangerous job and you never know.
>> They're Antifa.
>> Yeah they're Antifa.
Or is it the Portland PD who are Antifa?
If you believe Nick, what's his name?
Uh, from Fox Sorter.
>> Right. Right. Right. Right. Right.
Right.
>> Yeah. I mean, literally that. And that's
that's also what's so perverse and
twisted about it. It's like a right-wing
fever dream. Like, you know, Antifa the
the Portland police arrested me because,
you know, they're Antifa. No, the
Portland police arrested you because
they're [__] Okay. That's why
>> it's the opposite
>> because they're like they don't care
that you're a journalist. They don't
care that you're a Fox journalist. You
know that that's what happened here very
soon.
>> That is it.
>> Uh any questions we have to get to here?
Let's see. Um Chicago
residents have been posting videos of
them chasing ice out of their city. And
to be honest, it's rather hilarious.
I've seen some of these. I also like
that in Chicago there's that there's
that there's been viral videos like that
guy who trolled ICE who basically was on
his bike and he's like insulting them
and giving them the finger which by the
way is your first amendment right in the
United States right you can
>> that is constitutionally protected free
speech
>> annoying to me when cops say like oh you
know you you're not allowed to be
disrespectful yes you are
>> yeah you are
>> you are you can say [__] you suck my
dick I hate you. That's all legal. And
like the thing is, so anyway, this guy
did that and and then these fat ICE guys
are like chasing him and and he's like
he butts off and he's like all like in
like slaloming down the street in
Chicago as these guy I mean they look
ridiculous.
>> Yeah, they do. Yes, it's ridiculous.
>> It's like Keystone Cops.
All right. Well, shall we get to the
main event here? I think we should.
>> Yeah, I think we probably should.
>> So, John, I have thoughts. I know that
will surprise you. Um, so first of all,
I was thinking the first and foremost,
um, so the peace deal is first of all,
highly remarkable. Very happy to see it
going. I mean, you know, let's hope it
lasts. Okay. First of all, for years be
for through Democratic and Republican
presidencies alike, John, you and I have
been told that no one can control
Israel. That Israel is a force of nature
upon itself. That like Congress can't
take away their money because it's
guaranteed by law. The power of Apac is
too strong to be overcome. And anyway,
the Israelis wouldn't listen to us if we
pressured them because they're maniacs,
right? And
>> now it turns out, well, you apparently
you can pressure Israel and Donald
Trump.
>> Apparently, you can
>> the will.
>> It's about whether you want to or not.
And Donald Trump got so pissed off about
the strike against Qatar that he's just
like basically who knows what he said
behind the scenes, but I think it went
somewhere along the lines like this. Cut
the [__] or I'm cutting you off.
>> I think it was that simple.
>> We We called it, Ted.
>> We did call it.
>> Either either Gutter's a major major
non-NATO ally or it's not. It's either
going to host the world's largest air
force base or it's not.
>> Yep. Yep. And the thing is and the fact
that right now this look this is a piece
a deal we we should talk about like the
who's going to govern Gaza you know
aspect of this but but basically like
currently right Israel has lost Israel
had has to withdraw
>> um they're going to they're going to
they're going to have to send back um
you know they're going to get back their
hostages which is good for everybody um
they're going to get back you know
they're going to have to give back
hostages including prisoners who've been
convicted of crimes back to the
Palestinians, but the war is over.
Basically, that's it. Like you they have
to stop. And so really, I mean, it shows
that like if Donald, you know, when Joe
Biden and then Kla Harris sort of said
there's nothing we can do, that was a
lie.
>> And and we knew it was a lie. And and
those of us who said it was a lie were
like repeatedly ridiculed and shouted
down.
>> That's right. That's right. Beaten about
the face and head, I like to say.
>> Yeah.
>> That's that's what happened. And I mean
and so and the other thing, John, is
like we've also been told now by the
Israelis and their Zionist apologists
here in the States that they've been
allowing you there's no aid blockade.
you know, Hamas has been stealing the
aid. Um, you know, the they've been
allowing it all in. Well, it's part of
the deal. Ham the uh the the Oh, and we
were also told the UN can't be trusted.
UNRA is infested with Hamas.
>> Right. Right. Right. And they had to
destroy ENRA because it was a Hamas
front organization.
>> So, ENRA and the UN are now preparing to
flood the zone. So obviously ENRA is
trustworthy and obviously uh uh and and
John your signal just dropped. Um your
video just dropped. I don't know if you
can hear me.
>> Can you hear me?
>> Yeah, there you are.
>> Okay. So So Honor is trustworthy. The UN
has the aid ready to go in. Yeah.
>> And the Israelis were blocking it. I
mean this is now a this is now on the
record. There's no denying it ever. But
nobody's supposed to remember that stuff
about Enra, right? It was it was
expedient in the moment, but we're not
supposed to bring that up.
>> It's no longer relevant,
>> right? Because the Israelis control the
the narrative
>> and and I guess do you think I think
most people unlike us will have
forgotten about the whole UNRA [__]
>> Absolutely. Absolutely. Yes. And I mean
there people for who are, you know, who
are currently living in Gaza who were
fired from UNRA
over this [__]
>> Yes. Yes. Yes.
>> I wonder if they get their jobs back. I
bet they do.
>> John, let's talk about who's going to
rule Gaza. So basically, Israel's big
thing is it will not be Hamas. John, it
will be Hamas.
>> I mean, it will be Hamas
>> and it has to be, right? I mean, this is
kind of like who else is there? This
reminds me of Afghanistan when um we had
the when when the United States
sponsored the lawyer Jurga, right? And
the um and basically it was like all
parties are welcome to come except the
exiled king in Italy. We we'd rather not
have him around because he's actually
could might win this thing.
>> Remember him?
>> And yeah, he was old as [__]
>> Yeah.
>> 90 something years old.
>> Yeah. he would have been like the Joe
Biden of Afghanistan. Um, and then there
was and also the Taliban who represented
maybe 80% of Afghan politics at minimum.
Right? So here's the thing, right? Hamas
represents at least 80% of Gazan
politics of legit politics. There's
never been any opposition party allowed
to exist. It's like the Bach party. They
had a complete monopoly on political
power and jobs in Iraq, right? So, who
the [__] else is there? I mean,
Palestinian technocrats. I mean, quit
smoking hash. What the [__] are you guys
talking about? I mean, do you have any I
mean, they are joking, right? They just
don't know. Are they just floundering?
Are they flailing? Is that all it is?
>> They're floundering. You know, it's
funny. People like to think that they're
so perfectly in charge and then they
realize that they've been overtaken by
events and they're actually not really
in charge.
>> I like that.
Man, what a crazy world it is right now.
>> It is. I mean, it is crazy.
Um, also, I'd like to also say that, um,
and I, this is like I I come to praise
Donald Trump again. Um,
just, you know, just think about this
accomplishment. Okay, I know the Nobel
went the way it went, but let's be
serious here. I mean, and I didn't vote
for this man. Um, you know, I I voted
for Dr. Jill Stein, but it's October
10th. He took office January 20th. He
came in and ended the Gaza war within
less less than nine months, right? I
mean, so, you know, you if you if you I
mean, think about Richard Nixon. He
supposedly had a secret plan to end the
Vietnam War,
>> right?
>> Which he never got around to doing
really. Um,
>> yeah. And, and as history has shown, he
really didn't have a secret plan.
>> It was [__] Yeah. So, so you got,
so now, but Donald Trump apparently, I
don't know if I don't think he had any
plan, but he was just like wanted to end
it, and now it's over. Now again, Joe
Biden and the Democrats, they sat on
this [__] and let it happen for o over a
year,
>> you know, and and it's I I would argue
that like if that had if that war had
ended before election day, Kla Harris
would be president today.
>> I I agree with you.
>> Yeah.
>> So So I mean, and I don't think the
Democrats have learned their their their
their lesson here, you know.
>> Yeah. No. See, this is the problem with
the Democrats, Ted, is that they never
learn their lesson. Today, for example,
not I'm not changing the subject, I'm
just using this as an analogy. Uh there
was a piece in the Washington Post about
John Thoon, the Senate majority leader,
the Republican from South Dakota.
>> Um what's his strategy for dealing with
the Democrats on the government
shutdown? His strategy is to just wait
until the Democrats fold. And he said
it's because they always do fold. Well,
that's that's reasonable.
>> Yeah.
>> But not this. I don't think this time.
>> You don't think so?
>> I think they will.
>> Yeah. It'll take a while.
>> Not on the budget. But I'm just saying
on these other issues, there's no
strategy. There's no deep thinking that
goes into democratic policies.
>> That's true.
>> You know, like I' I said this on the
show that I used to have with Michelle.
When your campaign is vote for me
because I'm not the other guy, that's
not a winning strategy.
>> It almost never works. It did work for
Biden in 2020, but that was because of a
unique set of circumstances. And I think
I think look, I think the that went that
way because Trump acted like a maniac
over COVID.
>> Um, if it wasn't for that, to this day,
I will never understand why he ran away
from his own vaccine.
>> I have to agree. the vaccine was a major
political triumph. Um
>> it was
>> and then like and then he thought I mean
I know he was so deeply committed to his
base strategy
>> but I think in that that was a [__] up.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> what was operation
>> warp warp speed.
>> Um so John let's talk about this
guarantee.
I mean, so Trump issued a guarant Hamas
basically the holdup that's being
reported today was the the the the Hamas
was kind of like there's one thing we
really got to know. How do we know that
the Israelis aren't going to break the
ceasefire like they always do? How do we
know that they're not going to attack us
again? And Trump said, "I will
personally guarantee that I will not
allow the Israelis to do that."
>> Yeah, those are
>> what's the mechanism there? Let's say I
mean would that mean that the United
States would be
>> militarily obligated to respond and
attack Israel if or just to make a phone
call and just say cut the [__] or cut
them off financially. I mean what does
that look like?
>> That's the more likely scenario. Or if
you really want to get tough, I mean,
the last time we had an American
president really get tough with Israel,
it was George HW Bush where he suspended
housing loan guarantees and it nearly
brought down the Israeli government.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. Because we're never tough with the
Israelis. Never.
>> No. No. But but we keep being we keep we
keep saying like what can we do?
>> Yeah.
>> You know you know what we are like?
We're like a bad, you know, like you go
to the restaurant and there's the
terrible parent who the kids running
around raising hell, making life
miserable for all the other diners and
there's like it's I hate to say this,
it's usually the mom and the mom has a
very soft voice and she's like sitting
in her chair instead of getting up to
get her kid. She's like, "Honey, don't
do that to the nice man over there. Just
come back." That's what we're like with
Israel. Um we're like, "No, stop with
the please with the Palestinians. Yeah,
>> please be a little gentler with them.
Don't don't touch them. Don't mess up
their meal. Don't make them not eat.
>> It's like
>> that's it. That's it.
>> And Donald Trump has finally won for the
first time. Right. Like like you said,
since George HW Bush for the first time,
he's like, "Cut the shit." And they're
like, "Woof woof."
>> Yeah. That's right.
That's right. So, who knows? You know,
Donald Trump has surprised people before
and maybe he will be tougher
than any of us have have given him
credit for.
>> I think he will be because it's it's
gone great for him. You know what I
mean? Like he just did that and like
everyone loves him.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, you've got Ted R saying nice
things about you. You know, you're it's
like that's unusual.
>> Um and I'm not alone here. So, I think
he's going to be I I think he'll there
will be more. John, the the the we
talked about this at the top of the
show.
The reporters are going to start going
in. Everyone's going to see how [__]
horrible
>> Yeah.
>> Gaza, the state of Gaza is
>> um there's not going to be any
>> talk about a hellscape.
>> That's the hellscape. There's not going
to be
>> There's so many implications here. I I
don't even want to rank them. Israel's
reputation is going to be even sunk
deeper than it is now. And there's going
to be so um and I think there's not
going to be any appetite for exploiting
them like you know Trump Gaza or
whatever you know the the Tony Blair
plan all that shit's out the window.
There's just going to be a level of
international sympathy that's almost
analogous to the sympathy that there was
for Jews in 1945 after the Holocaust and
those camps were liberated and people
saw what they'd been through. There's
going to be that level of empathy and
sympathy and people are going to just
want they're going to they're going to
demand I this is so ironic. They're
going to demand that the Palestinians
deserve their own state after what
they've been through. I don't think
there's any I mean what do you think?
No, I agree. And isn't that what
US policy says the endgame is anyway? I
mean, since 1948, Harry Truman said an
independent Israel and eventually an
independent Palestine.
>> Okay. Well, that was 1948. And that's
reiterated every few years, you know, in
in talks. Okay, it's time for an
independent Palestine.
>> Well, and here's the thing that's
interesting, right? Like, okay, the
Kurds have been waiting longer than the
Palestinians independent state,
>> but the Kurds kind of don't need it the
way that the Palestinians need it. The
Palestinians, this war, the Gaza war,
proves that the Palestinians need a
state to be protected from the Israelis
or they're all going to be killed.
>> The Kurds don't have that problem. Yeah,
you know, there some of them, the Turks
have killed some of them, but it's not
the same thing. It's not on the same
scale. So I I think that's why the world
is going to be like they this is like
there's a difference between like want,
deserve, and need.
>> Yes,
>> that's right. That's a good point.
>> So all right, let's see.
>> Out of time.
>> Any I think we are out of time. Anything
else you want to talk about here?
>> No, I'm glad everybody had a chance to
join us.
>> Me, too. Um, thanks everybody for
joining us. Uh, have a great weekend. We
are going to be back, like I said,
Tuesday after the federal holiday. We
always take federal holidays off here,
even though neither of us are federal
worker, but whatever. Um, I guess I
guess if something really big happened,
we could always do an emergency show,
but um and we would do that, I think.
Um, but anyway, we're here Monday
through Friday, 900 a.m. Eastern time.
John, you're headed back to the land of
the tarantula and the mosquito. Are you
bringing any special gear? Any like
sprays or anything potions to make them
go away?
>> I'm buying some spray before I uh before
I get on the plane.
>> Don't get aerosols. They won't let you
on the plane.
>> They won't let you on. Yeah. Got to get
the cream.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You You need super super
toxic [__]
>> It's bad, man. Just thank God. I'm going
to knock on wood. I I don't have Zika
virus.
>> Yeah. Well, there's there's still they
don't that doesn't exist out out out in
Baja, does it?
>> I have no idea. I know those mosquitoes
could pick me up and fly me away.
>> Producer Robbie West uh is chiming in on
the chat that part three of John's
interview with your with me is going to
drop on Rumble Premium later today. So
for those of you who are on Rumble
Premium, uh there's part three out of
four is now available. All right guys,
thank you everyone and we will see you
on Tuesday.
>> Bye everybody.
>> John, fly safe.
>> Thank you.